Chapter 43.
Hark hist. Did you hear that noise? Kabako.
It was the middle watch, a fair moonlight. The seammen were standing in
a cordon extending from one of the freshwater butts in the waist to the
scuttle butt near the taff rail. In this manner they passed the buckets to fill
the scuttlebutt. Standing for the most part on the hallowed precincts of the
quarter deck, they were careful not to speak or rustle their feet. From hand to
hand the buckets went in the deepest silence, only broken by the occasional
flap of a sail and the steady hum of the unceasingly advancing keel. It was in
the midst of this repose that Archie, one of the cordon, whose post was near
the after hatches, whispered to his neighbor, a cholo, the words above.
Hist. Did you hear that noise, Kabako?
Take the bucket, will you, Archie? What noise do you mean? There it is again,
under the hatches. Don't you hear it? A cough. It sounded like a cough. Cough be
damned. Pass along that return bucket.
There again. There it is. It sounds like two or three sleepers turning over now.
Kamba, have done shipmate, will you?
It's the three soaked biscuits you eat for supper turning over inside of you.
Nothing else. Look to the bucket.
Say what you will, shipmate. I have sharp ears. I You are the chap, ain't
you? that heard the hum of the old Quakerus' knitting needles 50 mi at sea
from Nantucket. You're the chap. Grin away. We'll see what turns up. Harky
Kabako. There is somebody down in the after hold that has not yet been seen on
deck. And I suspect our old mogul knows something of it, too. I heard Stub tell
Flask one morning watch that there was something of that sort in the wind. Dish the bucket.